A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation photographs FA003
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Mexico
  - National Institute of Nutrition - Biochemistry
    Buildings, Models, Floor Plans,
  - National School of Agriculture - Graduate School, Chapingo
    Agriculture, Schools, Buildings, Models, Lectures, Laboratories, Students,
  - University of Chihuahua - Animal Science
    Group Portraits, Agriculture,
  - University of Mexico - Science Institutes - Institute of Biology
  - University of Mexico - Science Institutes - Institute of Chemistry
    Schools, Construction, Laboratories,
  - University of Mexico - Science Institutes - Institute of Geography
    Landscapes, maps,
  - University of Mexico - Science Institutes - Institute of Physics
    Schools, Laboratories, Portraits,
  - University of Mexico - Science Institutes - Physics
  - University of Sonora
    Cattle, Ranches, Group Portraits,
  - University of Veracruz - Veterinary Medicine
    Veterinary Medicine, Animals, Cattle, Laboratories,
  - Wheat Improvement
    Agriculture, Farming, Crops, Wheat,
  - Alcala de Stefano, Maximino
  - Institute Technologia de Monterrey
    Laboratories, Equipment,
  - Hospital Latino-Americano - Puebla
  - Department of Public Health - Vera Cruz
    Hospitals, Laboratories, Exam rooms, group Portraits,
  - Federal Department of Health 1927
    Buildings, Offices, Interiors, Group Portraits,
  - Federal Department of Health
    Hospitals, Buildings, Offices, Portraits, Group Portraits, Clinics, Exam rooms, Dispensaries, Laboratories, Vehicles,
  - Laboratories - Vaccines
    Vaccines, Animal testing, Cows, Laboratories,
  - Cuernavaca, Mor. - Training Station
  - National Institute of Anthropology and History
    Offices, Libraries,
  - Colegio de Mexico - Mexican History
    Libraries,
  - Colegio de Mexico - Seminary
    Offices, Group Portraits, Libraries, Micrographics,
  - Mexico City College - Creative Writing
    Writers, Group Portraits,
  - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Art Restoration
    Anthropology, Restoration,
  - National Institute of Anthropology and History - Photograph Album
    Libraries, Microphotography,
  - National School of Agriculture 1945-1947; 1964
    wheat field, research
- Nicaragua
  - General, 1936-1937
    Schools, Landscapes, Portraits, Rivers, Trains,
  - Knights - Rapid Method of Filling Keidel Tubes with Broth Media
  - Agriculture - Plant Pathology
  - RF Grant and Aids - Managua
  - University of Leon - Granada Institute, 1922-1923
    Schools, Medicine,
  - Granada - Lambert - Managua Hosptials 1922-1923
    Hospitals, Buildings, Group Portraits, wards,
  - Hookworm 1
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case studies, Children, Group Portraits, Doctors, Clinics, Houses, families, Sanitation, Privies, Demonstrations,
  - Hookworm 2
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case studies, families, Children, sanitation, Privies, Houses,
  - Molloy - Brine Flotation Method of Hookworm Diagnosis, 1921
    Laboratories, Equipment, Diseases, Hookworm, Diagnosis,
  - Molloy - A Demonstration of the Results of Hookworm Treatments, 1926
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case Studies,
  - Hulse - Nicaragua Malaria Survey - Report of La Puebla Pivas, 1921
    Diseases, Malaria, Landscapes, Houses, Streets,
  - Hulse, F. E. - Open Channel Drainage For Malaria Control, 1921
  - Hulse - Report of Malaria Control Drainage Post of Corinto, Nicaragua, June 1921
  - Malaria
    Diseases, Malaria, Drainage Ditches, Wetlands, Houses, Airplanes, Aerial views,
  - Hulse - A Fly Trap for Outdoor Privies of Deep and Shallow Pits, 1923
    Sanitation, Insects, traps, Privies, models,
  - Knights - Report of the Director of the Laboratorio de Hygiene Managua Nicaragua
  - Solorzano, Porfurio - Annual Report of Laboratories presented to General Diercto
    Laboratories, Clinics, Medical Exams,
  - Public Health Laboratories - Sanitary Engineering
    Laboratories, Clinics, Public Health, Group Portraits,
  - Yellow Fever
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Cisterns, Water collection, street scenes,
- Republic of Panama
  - General
    Diseases, Mycetoma, Group Portraits, Sanitation, Buildings,
  - Agriculture - Central American Corn Cooperative Program - Las Tablas
  - Crawford, Porter J. - Varous Health Subjects
    Sanitation, Drainage Ditches, Clinics, Medical exams, Group Portraits, Buildings,
  - School of Medicine - Panama City
    Schools, buildings,
  - Santo Tomas Hospital - School of Nursing, 1937-1939
    Schools, Buildings, Portraits,
  - Hospitals - United Fruit Company
  - Hookworm 1
    Diseases, Hookworm, Dispensaries, Group Portraits, Families, Case Studies, Children, Sanitation, Privies,
  - Hookworm 2
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case Studies, Sanitation, Privies, Houses, Group Portraits,
  - Hookworm 3
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case Studies, Children, Group Portraits, Sanitation, Privies, Houses, Villages,
  - Hookworm 4
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case Studies, Children, Group Portraits, Houses, Villages, Sanitation, Privies,
  - Malaria
    Diseases, Malaria, Sanitation, Houses, Wetlands, Drainage Ditches,
  - Public Health Demonstrations - Report 1934
    Sanitation, Privies, Houses, Drainage Ditches,
  - Burres - Additional Details of Privy Construction in Panama, 1918
  - Malaria, Health Unit, Tuberculosis
    Diseases, Malaria, Tuberculosis, Vaccinations, Sanitation, Rivers, Wetlands, Drainage Ditches, Offices,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    Public Health, Demonstrations, Medical Exams, Children, Drainage Ditches, Sanitaiton, Buildings, Families, Group Portraits,
  - Sanitary Engineering
    Laboratories, Buildings, Offices, Equipment,
  - Yellow Fever 1941
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Group Portraits, Medical Exams, Children,
  - Tuberculosis
    Diseases, Tuberculosis, Dispensaries, Buildings,
- Paraguay
  - General
    Group Portraits, Streetscenes, Markets,
  - Hospitals
  - Hookworm
    Diseases, Hookworm, Group Portraits, Children, Case Studies, Families, Houses, Sanitation, Privies,
- Peru
  - University of San Marcos - Medical School
    Schools, Buildings, Construction, Models,
  - University of San Marcos
    Schools, Laboratories, Equipment, Buildings, Group Portraits, Maps,
  - Peruvian University of Medical and Biological Sciences - University San Augustin
  - General
    Landscapes, Villages, Group Portraits,
  - Congress of Nurses - Lima, 1949
  - Agrarian University - Rojas
    Farming, Agriculture, Animals, Pigs, Cows,
  - Agriculture
    Agriculture, Farming, Crops, Potatoes, Bridges, Landscapes, Markets, Aerial Views, Cities, Streetscenes, Laboratories,
  - Agriculture - Plant Pathology
  - Institute of Andean Biology
    Buildings, Landscapes,
  - National School of Agriculture - La Molina
    Agriculture, schools, Classrooms, Laboratories, Animals,
  - Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia
    Buildings, Laboratories, Offices, Group Portraits,
  - University of San Marcos - Veterinary Medicine
    Veterinary Medicine, Animals, Buildings, Laboratories, Group Portraits, Conferences,
  - Yellow Fever
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Houses, Sanitation, Offices, Dispensaries, Water collection, Wetlands,
- El Salvador
  - General
    Group Portraits, Wetlands, Rivers,
  - Agriculture - Central American Corn Cooperative Program - San Andres
  - Corn
  - Ferrell, J. A. - Journal Covering Central American Journey, November - December
    Buildings, Hospitals, Houses, Streetscenes, Markets, Farming, Bananas, Temples, Monuments, Dispensaries,
  - Medical Sciences
    Buildings, Hospitals, Schools, Laboratories, Group Portraits,
  - University of El Salvador
    Schools, Hospitals, Pediatrics, Laboratories, Medical Exams,
  - Malaria
    Diseases, Malaria, Drainage Ditches, Maps,
  - Health Services
    Public Health, Laboratories,
  - Yellow Fever
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Cities, Street scenes, Water collection, cisterns, Group Portraits,
  - Tuberculosis
    Diseases, Tuberculosis, Buildings, Wards,
- Dominican Republic
  - Santo Domingo
    Diseases, Yaws, Leprosy, Conjunctivitis, Edema, Case Studies,
  - Santo Domingo
  - Hospital
  - Hookworm
    Diseases, Hookworm, Houses, Cases Studies, Sanitation, Privies, Markets,
  - Public Health Laboratory
- Uruguay
  - Hookworm 1916-1923
    Diseases, Hookworm, Case Studies, Children, Group Portraits, Doctors, Clinics, Dispensaries, Sanitation, Houses, Privies,
  - General
  - University of Montevideo - Obstetrical Physiology
    Periodicals, Publications,
  - Institute of Biological Sciences
    Laboratories, Equipment, Buildings, Construction, Specimines,
  - University of Montevideo
    Buildings, Construction, Laboratories, Equipment,
  - University of Montevideo - Veterinary Medicine
    Buildings, Schools, Veterinary Medicine, Animals, Horses, Group Portraits, Lectures, Laboratories,
- Venezuela
  - General
    Diseases, Elephantiasis, Madura, Group Portraits, Maps, Aerial Views, buildings,
  - Nursing
    Nurses, Hospitals, Wards, Dormitories, Group Portraits,
  - Agriculture - Genetics
  - Sanitary Engineering
    Sanitation, Sewers, Privies, Drainage Ditches, Offices, Trucks, Pesticides, DDT, Laboratories,
  - Hookworm
    Diseases, Hookworm, Dispensaries, Group Portraits, Children, Sanitation, Privies, Houses,
  - Malaria
    Diseases, Malaria, Wetlands, Drainage Ditches, Buildings, Laboratories, Group Portraits,
  - Sawyer - Public Health in Venezuela, August 1925
    Wetlands, Drainage Ditches, Water Reservoirs,
  - Yellow Fever
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Water Collection, Group Portraits, Rivers, Reservoirs,
  - Hanson - Venezuelan Views
    Diseases, Yellow Fever, Hookworm, Elephantiasis, Water collection, Cisterns, Reservoirs, Houses, Sanitation, Privies, Group Portraits, Case Studies, Wetlands, Aerial Views, Monuments, Railroads, Transportation, Vehicles,
- Great Britain
  - General
    medical equipment, laboratories, medical examinations, medical research
  - Molteno Institute - Mann - Mosquitos
    building
- England
  - John Innes Horticultureal Institute - Nuffield Innoculations
    building, inoculations
  - London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine
    bathing, building, infant inoculation
  - Oxford University - Sinclair (Human Anatomy)
    medical equipment, medical testing, research,
  - Police Systems
  - The Royal Institute of International Affairs
  - Burden Neurological Clinic
    medical equipment, research
  - Cambridge University
    research, equipment, buildings, interiors, medical specimens, laboratories
  - Galton Laboratory - Genetics
    medical research
  - London School of Hygiene - Bilharziasis Research 1961-1968
    medical examinations
  - Maudsley Hospital - Psychiatry - Eysenck
    psycological testing
  - National Hospital for Nervous Diseases, Queen Square
    laboratories, interior and building destruction, patients
  - Oxford University - Physiology
  - Roffey Park Rehabilitation Center
    Drawings of buildings and interiors
  - Royal College of Surgeons - Library
    building destruction, skulls
  - Royal Society of Medicine - Medical Library
    microfilm filming and processing equipment, building inscription
  - St. Thomas Hospital Medical School - Physiology
    doctors, x-ray equipment, physical measurement
  - Tavistock [Square] Clinic
    building, children playing
  - Queen Charlotte's Hospital
    buildings, laboratories, doctors, library
  - University of Birmingham - Pyschiatry
    scientists, electric equipment,
  - University College, London
    building, laboratories, scientists, researchers, buildings, interiors, dining room, library, hosptial, operating rooms, King and Queen,
  - University of London
    building models
  - University of London - Royal Ear Hospital
    hospital interiors, hosptial beds, hallways, operating rooms, building
  - Birkbeck College - X-ray Analysis
    equipment
  - Birmingham University - Science
    building construction, lab equipment, scientists
  - Bristol University - Anatomy and Physics
    cells, buildings
  - Brieger, E.M. - Electron Microsopy
    cells, animal biology
  - Cambridge University
    scientists, laboratories, animals, equipment
  - London School of Hygiene - Tropical Nutrition
    diagrams
  - Marine Biological Station, Plymouth Laboratory
    boat, man in mud, laboratories, lab equipment,
  - Kings College - Molecular Biology
    cells, equipment
  - Oxford University
    bottles, models, equipment, scientists, researchers,
  - Rothamsted Experiment Stations - Protein Research
  - Royal Institution - Davy-Faraday Research Laboratory
    building, theatre interior
  - Hospitals
    buildings
  - Hookworm
    diseased arm, Hookworm
  - Public Health - Streeter
    landscapes, fields, houses, water treatment facilities, sewage plants,
  - Health Services
    buildings, laboratories, libraries,
  - Public Health Education - London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine 1929-30
    buildings, laboratories, libraries, auditorium, interiors, landscape, poster
  - Oxford University - Bodleian Library
    buildings, construction, libraries, tablet, interiors,
  - Bodelian Library
    library interior
  - British Museum
    ariel view,
  - Cambridge University
  - Dartington Hall - Theatre School
    buildings, landscape, actors
  - London School of Economics, 1933, 1937-38
    buildings,
  - London School of Oriental Studies, 1933, 1962
    building models,
  - Manchester Public Libraries - Microfilm
    filming equipment, microfilm camera
  - National Central Library - American Bibliography
    library, card catalog, destruction,
  - RIIA - Toynbee
    park, river, trees, people
  - University of Bristol - Drama
    theatre models, actors, dancers
  - University of Birmingham - Elizabethan Literature
    group of people
  - University College, London - Library
    books, buildings, damage, destruction
  - University of Leeds - Library
  - British Institute of Economic Research
    library interiors,
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs
    interior, doorway,
  - Royal Statistical Society
    speaker, audience, group photo,
  - University of London, Advanced Legal Studies - Sayles
    book letter drawing
- Ireland
  - Queen's University, Belfast
    buildings, interiors, laboratories, classroom,
  - Royal College of Surgeons
    buildings, libraries, laboratories, painting, interiors, classrooms, destruction
  - Trinity College, Dublin
  - University College, Cork
  - University College, Dublin
    laboratories, classrooms, hallway
  - University College, Galway
  - University College, Dublin - Biochemistry
    laboratories, scientists, equiment, buildings, portrait,
  - Trinity College, Dublin
    buildings, library interior
- Scotland and Shetland Islands
  - University of Edinburgh - Family Practice
    doctors, patients, lab equipment, group photos,
  - University of Edinburgh - Nursing Studies Unit
    building, library, staff, students,
  - Rowett Research Institute - Animal Nutrition 1958-1959
    laboratories, researchers, scientists, equipment, building,
- Wales
  - Cardiff Mental Hospital
    scientists, laboratories, animals, equipment,
  - University of Wales
    laboratory interiors,
- Australia
  - General
    portrait of J.D. Legge
  - Australian National University - Microbiology
    architectual floor plans
  - Australia National University - Medical School
    buildings, aerial shots
  - Aborigines
  - Hirsh Trip Diary 1916, vol. 1
    scientists, fieldwork, poster, train, latrines, toilets,
  - Australia Institute of Tropical Medicine 1921-1922
  - Children's Hospital, Melbourne - Pediatrics 1959-1962
    charts
  - Hall Institute
    swamps, row boating, laboratory equipment, egg testing, microscope particle images
  - University of Sydney 1924-1936
    buildings, laboratory, operating theatre, anatomy museum, construction
  - University of Sydney - Clinical Laboratory
    building, plaque
  - University of Western Australia - Electron Microscope
    laboratory equipment, laboratory interiors, microscope cell images, floor plan
  - Natural Sciences - Agriculture 1926-1932
    aborigines, natives, tribes, landscape, outback, desert
  - Bowen (Floating Sphere)
    diagram, drawing
  - Commonwealth Scientific Organization
    floor plans, equipment, aerial view,
  - Commonwealth Scientific Organization - Radio Telescope 1959-1962
    radio telescope, construction, governor, equipment, audience, aerial views of land, landscape,
  - University of Melbourne - Biochemistry, Physiology, Zoology 1961-1962
    buildings, sheep, animal testing, surgery,
  - University of Queensland - Marine Biology
    lab students, turtle, microscope, coral reef
  - Hookworm - Baldwin, Cooling Survey Report #20
    aborigines, ant hill,
  - Hookworm 1918-1922
    hookworm, disease, privy, latrines, children, adults, aborigines, cabinets, village homes, office, staff, hookworm staff, Dr. Lambert lecture
  - Baldwin and Cooling - Survey Report #21
    aboriginies, river
  - Burnell and McKee - Bound Volume - Survey Report #11
    horsedrawn carriage, creek, river, wading
  - Cilento (Bound Vol.) Survey Report #31
    soil, gardens, drains,buildings,
  - Murray and Metcalfe - Survey Report #29
    sailboats, gangosa in girl, pearl shells on a beach, animal meat,
  - Robertson - Survey Report #2
    privy, water containers, change house,
  - Shane - Survey Report #13
    tents, campground,
  - Sawyer - Annual Report, 1921
    camel team, pineapple farm, latrine, privy, panstead, natives washing
  - Sawyer and Ping - Survey Report #17
    privies, aborigine homes, diseased ground, dead tree, soil,
  - Special Report No. 1, 1920 - Educational Exhibit of the Hookworm Campaign
    Hookworm exhibit, buildings, children, privies, landscape, adults, disease, village, aboriginies, natives, examiner, interiors, inspector,
  - Sawyer - Annual Reports 1920
    latrine, hookworm exhibit sign, native, aboriginies, office building, children
  - Charlton - Survey Report #22
    natives, hookworm disease, horse transportation,
  - Charlton - Completed Area Report #12
    sugar cane fields and mill, river
  - Paine - Completed Area Report #15
    miners, mining, panstead, latrine,
  - Paine - Completed Area Report #16
    panstead, aboriginal hut, forrest station, sugarcane field, building,
  - Sweet - Annual Report, 1922
    mining, tree, aborigine ceremony, farm, refuse, backyard
  - Sweet - Survey Report # 25
    aborigine ceremony, latrines, burial site, trees,
  - Sweet - Survey Report #28
    sugarcane field, cows, farm
  - Sawyer, Sweet, Shaw - Survey Report #24
    buildings, fence
  - Completed Area Report #1
    privies, panstead cabinets,
  - Jones - Completed District Sanitary Report #3
    refuse, backyard, sanitary van, horse drawn carriage, storm water drain,
  - Jones - Completed District Sanitary Report #5
    equipment, soil, fertilizer
  - Jones - Completed District Sanitary Report #7
    sanitary pans, trenches,
  - University of Sydney 1929-1930
  - Institute for Strategic Studies
    portrait, library, men,
  - Queensland Institute of Medical Research
    building, field station,
- Cook Islands - South Pacific Islands (RG 1.1)
  - General
    portraits of native Samoans
- New Zealand
  - General
    houses, housing
  - Otago University 1924, 1927
  - University of Auckland - Marine Biology
    submarine growth chamber, tube, docks, light chamber
  - Kanitane-Harris Hospital
    buildings, flowers
  - Hookworm
    Figian men with hookworm display
  - General - 1926, 1932, 1939
    latrines, dancing mask, native nurses, buildings, group,
- Cook Islands - Record Group 5
  - General - 1926, 1932, 1939
- Fiji - Gilbert and Ellice Islands, Pitcairn Island
  - Hookworm
    hookworm, disease, natives, Figians, housing, houses, buildings, river, sugar mill, privies, men, women, children, groups, bottles of hookworm, latrines, tools, molds, bamboo
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    group photo, laboratory, equipments, building, scientists, cadaver,
  - Yaws
    inoculations, shots, patients, yaws, child
  - General
  - Medical Sciences
    Figians, natives, students, portraits, buildings, children, group portrait,
  - Anthropology
    Figian village, Figians, natives, hut, housing
  - General
    natives, polynesians, Figians, canoes, housing, houses, plants, trees, village buildings, bones, casket, children, latrines, lagoon,
  - General
    Langi, tombs, stones, buildings, cemetery, homes, housing, trees, blow-holes, Togans, natives, Queen, Prince, privy, latrines, flying foxes,
  - Hookworm
    Hookworm, disease, latrine construction, yards, prince, group, natives,
  - Central Nurses School - Suva, Fiji
    Nurses, group portraits, native dress.
- Gilbert and Ellice Islands
  - General
- Tonga Islands - Record Group 5
  - General
  - Hookworm
- Fiji - Gilbert and Ellice Islands, Pitcairn Island - Nursing
  - Central Nurses School - Suva, Fiji
- Caribbean Region and Central America
  - Corn Improvement - Nicaragua
    corn fields, corn stalks, building, corn inspection, equipment
  - Corn Improvement - Panama
    corn fields, corn stalks, corn inspection,
  - Kumm, H.W.
    pipes, drainage, building, concrete gutters, ditches, maps, equipment,
  - General
    latrines, canals, latrine construction, scenery, landscape, laboratory researcher, equipment,buildings, natives, viles, bottles, patients, children, men, women, hookworm treatment, disease treatment, disease education,
  - Corn Improvement - Costa Rica
    corn fields, corn inspection, corn stalks,
  - Corn Improvement - El Salvador
    corn fields, corn stalks, corn inspection, buildings,
  - Corn Improvement - Guatemala
  - Corn Improvement - Honduras
    corn fields, corn stalks, corn inspection, ears, corn husks,
  - Corn Improvement - Maps
    Central American Maps indicating corn and agronomist amounts
  - Report of Intinerary of H.H. Howard Feb. 15-May 10, 1921
    septic tanks, privies, latrines,
  - Caribbean Marine Biological Institute - Zaneveld
    building,
  - Corn Improvement-Costa Rica Primera Reuion Centro Americana Mehoramiento de Maiz
    group photos, men, speakers,
  - Malaria
    drainage ditches, irrigation, gutters, pipes, water pumps, building, mosquito breeding and capturing places,
  - Molloy, D.M.
    delegates, bridge, buildings, mossy foot, onchocerciasis, parade, group photos
  - Molloy, D.M.
    latrine, privy, construction plant,
- Guyana (formerly British Guiana)
  - General
  - Elephantiasis 1914-1916
    Elephantiasis, legs, adults, man, woman,
  - Rose
    Hospitals, buildings,
  - Hookworm
    Hookworm, disease, latrines, privies, adults, children, houses, housing, market, natives, East Indians, baby, infant, village, drains, ditches, trenches, buildings, huts,
  - Staff and Offices 1914-1916
    staff, group photos, offices, buildings,
  - Malaria
  - Public Health Demonstrations
  - Connor - Log of the Yellow Fever Commission to the British, French, and Dutch..
    tanks, vats, natives, aerial views, drainage canal, water supply, yellow fever, disease, adults, houses, housing,
  - Humanities and Arts
  - Tuberculosis
    buildings, group photo, men and woman
- Belize (formerly British Honduras)
  - Hookworm
    Hookworm, disease, privies, infection, adults, boys, groups, children, houses, housing, huts,
  - Yellow Fever
    buildings, houses, housing, yards, freight cars, camp, wooden barrels, garbage, trash, oilers, street drains, drainage, canals, Belize streets,
  - Humanities and Arts
- Canada
  - General
    buildings and Cross Reference sheets
  - Manitoba
    medical bottles, dogs, Indians, natives, airplane, building, nurse, infant, baby, incubators, Impinger apparatus, equipment,
  - New Brunswick
    exhibit, baby care, dishes, cleaning, washing, school children, cooking, students, mothers,
  - McGill University - Neurology
  - Medical Sciences (by University)